# **Andrey Chasovskikh**

E-mail: andrey.chasovskikh@gmail.com

Phone number: +7 921 321 5519
Skype: andrey.chasovskikh
Website: http://andreycha.info

Visa status: non-EU citizen, visa is required

#### **Profile**

I'm a software developer with 7 years of experience in the area. My experience includes development of both frontend and backend applications, with a bias to backend development: financial software, ETL solutions, and medical information systems.

### **Skills**

Programming languages: C#, Java, Delphi, Pascal

Technologies: .NET, WinForms, WPF, Silverlight, LINQ, ADO.NET, PLINQ, async/await,

T-SQL, XML, Windows Phone, Smart GWT, DevExpress, Infragistics

Databases: MS SQL Server

IDE: MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, NetBeans, Borland Delphi

CVS: TFS, git (basics), Subversion
Bugtracking: TFS, Jira, Gemini, Redmine
CI: TeamCity, Cruise Control

Additional tools: MSTest, xUnit, JUnit, ReSharper, memory and performance profilers

Languages: Russian (native), English (working proficiency)

Other: OOP, multithreaded and asynchronous programming, test driven

development, clean code, agile methodologies, code review

### **Professional experience**

Broadridge Financial Solutions (Paladyne Systems before Sept. 2011), St. Petersburg, Russia. March 2011 – present

Position: senior software developer (since August 2014)

- Taking part in developing new product for reference data quality and arbitration, which consists of a document storage and a number of services:
  - integrated with Security Master product: loading and keeping up-to-date 10+ mln entities
  - developed number of input and output adapters for data transformation engine
  - implemented apply/diff algorithm for document storage
  - bugfixing and adding various features across the application
- Took part in developing and supporting application for managing securities reference data, Security Master. This included estimating, designing and developing features (from UI to backend code and database), supporting existing functionality, writing tests (mostly employing TDD) and technical documentation, code review, solving client issues. Developed major features for a number of releases:
  - designed and developed 'Custom Dictionaries' feature
  - developed custom FormPF solution based on 'Custom Calculated Fields' feature; this helped to keep the client
  - took part in developing 'Auto-Failover' feature
  - took part in high-level design of 'Custom Calculated Fields' feature, developed it from scratch
- Took part in supporting complementary product for loading reference data from vendors into other products, ETL Manager, which is written in Java. Mentored two new developers for 6 months.

**Keywords:** C#, Java, T-SQL, Infragistics, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, MS SQL Server, IIS, Tomcat, TFS, git, Jira, TeamCity, TDD, RhinoMock, NSubstitute, Mockito, Scrum

#### BrainSystems, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2010 - March 2011

Position: software developer

- Developed e-archive system prototype for museum of Russian Academy of Arts: full application design and development.
- Took part in developing Java web application for St.Petersburg medical municipal institution, both front-end and backend parts.

**Keywords:** C#, Silverlight, Entity Framework, WCF RIA Services, MS SQL Server, Java, Smart GWT, Oracle, Jasper Reports, JBoss, NetBeans, SVN, Redmine

#### Kostasoft, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2008 – September 2010

Position: software developer

- Took part in developing and supporting medical information system, Avicenna.NET. This included writing new functionality (from UI to backend code), supporting existing codebase and writing technical documentation.
- · Initiated using of weekly sprints and product backlog.
- Was leading weekly retrospective meetings.

Keywords: C#, T-SQL, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, SVN, Gemini

### Academic experience

### St. Petersburg State Polytechnical University. February 2010 - February 2014

Have lead exercises and several lectures for "Databases" course (MS SQL Server, T-SQL) every spring semester.

#### Education

#### 2010 - 2012, St. Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Postgraduate student (unfinished).

### 2004 - 2010, St. Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Specialist degree in Software Engineering. GPA: 4.5/5.0.

# Talks & publications

- "async/await: avoiding common mistakes", .NEXT Moscow, December 2014
- "Windows Phone applications security", HackInParis, June 2013
- "Inspection of Windows Phone applications", BlackHat Abu Dhabi, December 2012
- "Clustering algorithms overview", <a href="http://web-analitik.info/">http://web-analitik.info/</a>, September 2010

## Certificates & diplomas

- 3<sup>rd</sup> prize at "VK.com messenger for Windows Phone" contest (2012)
- MCTS: Windows Application Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 (2011)
- Brainbench C# 3.0 Fundamentals Master (2011)
- Microsoft IT Case Cup semifinalist diploma (2011)
- Exigen Services' ".NET Workshop", letter of archievement (2009)

### References

- Alexey Zotov, SPbSPU associate professor, <a href="mailto:a.zotov@bssys.com">a.zotov@bssys.com</a>
- Andrew Jackovlev, BrainSystems CEO, <u>Andrew.Jackovlev@brainsystems.ru</u>
- Eugene Kogan, Kostasoft CEO, ekogan@kostasoft.spb.ru